Natalia Echeverry Giraldo

Shadyside, Pittsburgh, PA verrynatalia.github.io/verrynatalia

SUMMARY

As a graduate student in the MS-HCI program at RIT, specializing in Instructional Systems Design, I am uniquely positioned to create engaging and effective online learning experiences. I have successfully designed accessible (508 and WCAG-compliant) self-paced e-learning modules with modern authoring tools and learning management systems. I have experience working under the ADDIE model and SAM Agile. In my role as a learning designer and program officer, I have also demonstrated strong project management skills. Additionally, I am proficient with Adobe Creative Suite, Figma/Adobe XD, and Articulate 360. Moving forward, I am excited to expand my skill set to include usability testing and user research, particularly in the area of learning platforms and modules. I am also interested in using visual analytics tools to explore online course data.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Learning Developer Consultant

World Bank Group HQ, Remote

June 2022 to February 2023

- Collaborated with World Bank, WaterAid, and UNICEF water, sanitation, and hygiene (WASH) specialists to update and adapt WaterAid's online program on inclusive WASH practices.
- Coordinated inter-agency activities and work plan schedules, ensuring successful project outcomes.
- Designed and developed seven accessible interactive e-learning modules (using Articulate Rise 360) and a course page (using Moodle) on UNICEF's learning management system.

Program Officer

November 2019 to May 2022

UNICEF NYHQ, Remote

- Administered UNICEF's learning management system with 200-thousand users, managing course pages, user roles, and tracking course reports.
- Facilitated communication and coordination between program experts and vendors/consultants to create over a hundred e-learning modules. Oversaw project stages from analysis to development, held regular meetings, provided feedback, and monitored progress.
- Conducted training and demo sessions for course owners on managing and monitoring course pages, including accessing course reports, learning analytics, uploading content, and creating new components.
- Managed and supervised the Learning & Technology team's internship program, selecting and mentoring interns in areas such as instructional design, e-learning development, learning management system ad ministration, and learning analytics.

Learning Designer

January 2016 to June 2017

UNDP RBLAC, Bogota D.C.

- Designed and developed over 10 e-learning modules using Articulate Storyline for government officials in Latin America and the Caribbean.
- Conducted needs assessments and collaborated with subject matter experts to ensure the modules effectively met learning objectives.
- Coordinated the redesign of RBLAC's learning platform (Moodle) with colleagues and the vendor, resulting in a more user-friendly and engaging experience for learners.

Learning Advisor

March 2016 to April 2016

Universidad Javeriana, Bogota D.C.

- Designed a quality assurance rubric for JaverianaX on the EdX platform and used it to review their massive online courses (MOOCs).
- Provided feedback for educational and accessibility improvement of JaverianaX courses to reduce learner support queries and ensure better learning experiences.

Natalia Echeverry Giraldo

Shadyside, Pittsburgh, PA verrynatalia.github.io/verrynatalia

Instructional E-Learning Designer

February 2014 to November 2015

Inter-American Development Bank HQ, Washington D.C.

- Designed and developed e-learning modules for employees and government officials in Latin America and the Caribbean.
- Updated onboarding modules for IDB's country directors.
- Created visual elements for massive online courses (MOOCs) on IDBx EdX platform.

E-Learning Developer

September 2013 to March 2014

Inter-American Development Bank HQ, Remote

- Updated and debugged interactive modules for IDB's onboarding program, ensuring they were functional and up-to-date.
- Designed and developed a new onboarding module, incorporating interactive features and multimedia elements to enhance engagement and learning outcomes.
- Worked closely with subject matter experts to ensure the content was accurate and relevant to learners.
- Conducted testing and quality assurance checks to ensure the module was error-free and user-friendly.

EDUCATION

Master of Science—Human-Computer Interaction, Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY—US 2024 Graduate Degree—Product Design, Universidad Jorge Tadeo Lozano, Bogota D.C.—Colombia 2011 Bachelor of Sciences in Visual Arts, Universidad Javeriana, Bogota D.C.—Colombia 2008

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT & TRAINING

Applying the Quality Matters Rubric for CPE, Quality Matters, Washington D.C.—2015 Principles of Applied Statistics, Rochester Institute of Technology, Online—2021 Introduction to programming in Java, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA—2020 LearnLab, Simon Initiative Summer School, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA—2022

SKILLS

Platforms/Tools: Figma, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, H5P, Rise 360, Storyline 360, Tableau, Moodle, Totara, OpenEdX, WordPress

Design: Research, Prototyping, Usability Testing, Heuristic Evaluation, Project Management, SAM Agile, Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG), Section 508

Programming: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, R